NELSON TORRES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(615)997-4743

NelsonTorresJr330@gmail.com

https://github.com/Nelsontorresjr330

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nelsontorresjr330/

nelsontorresjr330.github.io

PREVIOUS PROJECTS

Civilization Simulation in Python (CS5260 - Introduction to Artificial Intelligence) Image Processor for Android in Java (CS5253 - Parallel Programming) Snake in C++ for Arduino (Personal Project)

Tkinter Personal Calender using Google API in Python (Personal Project) Github Pages Portfolio Site in React

EDUCATION

Master of Science

Vanderbilt University

Jan 2023 - Apr 2024

3.74 GPA - Computer Science Major Notable Coursework : Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Model-Based Development, Computer Networks, Parallel Programming, Web Based System Architecture

Bachelor of Science Middle Tennessee State University

Aug 2018 - Dec 2022

3.45 GPA - Computer Engineering & Applied Physics Double Major Notable Coursework : Discrete Structures and Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Circuit Design, Microprocessor Design, Programming Language Design, Assembly and Computer Design

Vanderbilt Data Anaytics Bootcamp

May 2019 - Feb 2020

Completed an intensive Vanderbilt Data Analytics Boot Camp, focusing on practical applications of data manipulation, analysis, and visualization techniques. Acquired advanced skills in Python, SQL, Tableau, and machine learning, preparing for data-driven decision-making in a professional setting

PROFILE

I am a Vanderbilt University Alumni with a Masters in Computer Science and MTSU Alumni with a B.S. in Computer Engineering & Applied Physics (Computer Science Concentration) & a French Minor. My expertise revolves around database management, ETL work, and SQL development in part due to completing a Vanderbilt University Data Analytics Bootcamp. I am currently working as an SDE 2 for Amazon based out of Nashville, TN.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer 2

Amazon

June 2024 - Present

- Working on developing a proprietary AWS SCADA system.
- Work invlolves data ETL, PLC programming, Python, AWS, SQL and usage of internal Amazon Development Tools for CI/CD & Source Control.

Full Stack Software Engineer

IPro Systems

Oct 2022 - June 2024

- Develop and debug backend APIs and frontend UI/UX changes
- Worked with Python, Boto3, Docker, Java, SQL, FastAPI, AGILE, Node.JS, Spark and AWS
- Notable projects: AWS Redshift DDL, Massive ETL of Tenant from legacy systems, Development of mission critical billing processes

Controls Engineer Intern

Automation NTH

Jun 2022 - Oct 2022

- Went through the NTH University program as an Intern to prepare working as a Controls Engineer for the organization
- Programming PLCs, Designing schematics & electrical diagrams via AutoCAD, Constructing & wiring panels.

Contractor / Data Manager

J&N Carpentry

May 2020 - Jun 2022

- · Creating VBA scripts to automate document creation
- · Managed SQL DB to handle sensative information
- · Managed employees and met with customers

Physics Tutor

MTSU Physics Department

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

 Helped students understand concepts thought throughout various courses ranging from Introductory Calc-Based Physics to Modern Physics